Guide to the Freshman Year, Yale University, Student Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Freshman Year, Yale University, student records
1903-1967
RU 879
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
110.75
The records consist of student records maintained by the Yale Freshman Year.
Yale University. Freshman Year
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 12-D (YRG 12-D), Student records for the Yale Freshman Year.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is partially restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of student records maintained by the Yale Freshman Year.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
College freshmen; College students; Yale University -- Freshmen; Yale University -- Students; Yale University. Freshman Year
- Student entrance cards, 1903-1954; Accession 19ND-A-091 (Box 100–118, Box 118–134)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2030
  - Entrance cards, 1950-1953
    - A-Berl, 1950-1953 (Box 1)
    - Berm-Byr, 1950-1953 (Box 2)
    - Ca-Cypr, 1950-1953 (Box 3)
    - Da-Emos, 1950-1953 (Box 4)
    - En-Gar, 1950-1953 (Box 5)
    - Gat-Gyp, 1950-1953 (Box 6)
    - Ha-Hor, 1950-1953 (Box 7)
    - Hos-Key, 1950-1953 (Box 8)
    - Lh-Maso, 1950-1953 (Box 10)
    - Mass-Ng, 1950-1953 (Box 11)
    - Ni-Por, 1950-1953 (Box 12)
    - Pos-Roz, 1950-1953 (Box 13)
    - Kh-Lez, 1950-1953 (Box 9)
    - Roz-Simm, 1950-1953 (Box 14)
    - Simo-Sym, 1950-1953 (Box 15)
    - Ta-Walk, 1950-1953 (Box 16)
    - Walker-Zys, 1950-1953 (Box 17)
    - A-Mooney (supplement), 1950-1953 (Box 18)
    - Moore-Z (supplement), 1950-1953 (Box 19)
  - Entrance Cards - Administrative withdrawn
    - 1947-1951 (Box 20–21)
    - 1952 (Box 22)
    - 1954 (Box 23)
  - Entrance Cards - Adjusted & Withdrawn, 1954 (Box 24)
  - Entrance Cards - Rejected, 1954 (Box 25–26)
  - Entrance Cards - Withdrawn, 1954 (Box 26)
  - Entrance Cards - Reserve withdrawn, 1954 (Box 26)
  - Entrance Cards, circa 1903-1946 (Box 27–99)
- Grades, circa 1920-1955; Accession 19ND-A-093 (Box 1–10)
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2031
  Scope and Contents
  No inventory available.
- Preliminaries, circa 1907-1923; Accession 19ND-A-095
  The materials are open for research.
  - circa 1923 (Box 1)
  - 1907-1909 (Box 2)
  - 1910-1911 (Box 3)
  - 1912 (Box 4)
  - 1913-1915 (Box 5–6)
- Student grades, circa 1941-1965; Accession 19ND-A-096 (Box 1–4)
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2041
- Records of ex-students, circa 1925-1959; Accession 19ND-A-098
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2035
  - 1925x (Box 1)
  - 1926x (Box 2)
  - 1926-1927x (Box 3)
  - 1927x (Box 4)
  - 1927-1928x (Box 5)
  - 1929x (Box 6)
  - 1930x (Box 7)
  - 1931x (Box 8)
  - 1932x (Box 9)
  - 1933x (Box 10)
  - 1934x (Box 11)
  - 1935x (Box 12)
  - 1936x (Box 13)
  - 1937x (Box 14)
  - 1938-1939x (Box 15)
  - 1939-1940x (Box 16)
  - 1940-194?x (Box 17)
  - 194?-1943x (Box 18)
  - 1943-1944x (Box 19)
  - 1944-1945x (Box 20)
  - 1945-1945Wx (Box 21)
  - 1945Wx (Box 22)
  - 1945W-1946x (Box 23)
  - 1946-1947x (Box 24)
  - 1948-1949x (Box 25)
  - 1949-1949M-1950x (Box 26)
  - 1950-1952x (Box 27)
  - 1952-1953x (Box 28)
  - 1953-1954x (Box 29)
  - 1955x (Box 30)
  - 1956x (Box 31)
  - 1957-1958x (Box 32)
  - 1958-1959x (Box 33)
- Class schedules for students of the Freshman Year, circa 1925-1945; Accession 19ND-A-101
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2021
- Student records for students withdrawn from the Freshman Year, circa 1964-1967; Accession 19ND-A-102 (Box 1–2)
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2043
- Class records and memoranda, 1920-1960; Accession 19ND-A-441
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2036
  - Class records (grades, class lists, etc.), classes of 1924 - 1945W, 1920-1945 (Box 1, Folder 1 - 22)
  - Droppers, classes of 1924 - 1950, 1920-1950 (Box 1, Folder 23 - 49)
  - Samples of forms, memoranda, etc., 1945 September-1947 June (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Mimeographed notices, etc.
    - 1947 Jun (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - 1947 Sep (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Re 1946, 1943-1945 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Class of 1945W, 1942-1943 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Class of 1945, 1941-1942 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Class of 1944, 1940-1941 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - 1939-1940 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - 1951-1953 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - 1959-1960 (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - 1957-1958 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - 1955 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - 1953-1954 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - C.A.A. - Civil Pilot Training Course, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Air raid precautions, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Personnel forms, 1920-1930 (Box 3, Folder 65 - 66)
  - Schedule pamphlets, 1946-1951 (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - Personnel - schedule pamphlets, 1930-1946 (Box 3, Folder 68 - 69)
- Student record cards of the Freshman Year for the Classes of 1940-1955, 1936-1955; Accession 2001-A-065
  - Class of 1940
    - Abrams-Geoffrey (Box 1)
    - Wilcox-Zimbalist
  - Class of 1941
    - Aber-Smith (Box 2)
    - Smith-Zucker (Box 3)
  - Class of 1942
    - Abelson-Kasimer (Box 3)
    - Katz-Zucker (Box 4)
  - Class of 1943
    - Abelt-Campbell (Box 4)
    - Campion-Selingson (Box 5)
    - Segnalla-Zeldes (Box 6)
  - Class of 1944
    - Abbott-Hoover (Box 6)
    - Hope-Zischke (Box 7)
  - Class of 1945
    - Abell-Lashnits (Box 8)
    - Lawless-Zelle (Box 9)
  - Class of 1945w
    - Abbott-Baker (Box 9)
    - Baldridge-Laranger (Box 10)
    - Lord-Zollner (Box 11)
  - Class of 1945wo
    - Ackley-Chapman (Box 11)
    - Chism-Zundell (Box 12)
  - Class of 1945wf
    - Aibel-Wilson (Box 12)
    - Allingham-Vetault (Box 12)
  - Class of 1946
    - Abrahamson-Langer (Box 12)
    - Leathers-Zimmerman (Box 13)
    - Ackert-Sanford (Navy-Marines-CoastGuard) (Box 13)
    - Satalia-Zoni (Navy) (Box 14)
    - Adams-Zoller (Navy-Irregular) (Box 14)
    - Abbott-Wright (Civilians) (Box 14)
    - Aase-Kilkaitis (March) (Box 14)
    - Kish-Zimmerman (Box 15)
    - Adams-Weyhauser (March -Civilians) (Box 15)
  - Class of 1947
    - Abbott-Palmer (Box 15)
    - Palmer-Young (Box 16)
    - Ackerman-Zabriskie (Box 16)
    - Bigleman-Whittemore (November) (Box 16)
    - Abarca-Yoke (November-Civilians) (Box 16)
    - Akin-Wolfe (March) (Box 17)
    - Anderson-Wright (March-Civilians) (Box 17)
  - Class of 1948
    - Adil-Nichols (Box 17)
    - Norman-Zuckerman (Box 18)
    - Amendola-Zuckerman (Navy) (Box 18)
  - Class of 1949n
    - Abbott-Wright (Navy) (Box 18)
  - Class of 1949
    - Adams-Connally (November) (Box 18)
    - Connors-Zyndell (November) (Box 19)
    - Abrons-Niewenhous (March) (Box 19)
    - Nolan-Zimmerman (March) (Box 20)
  - Class of 1950
    - Darnell-Ethridge (Box 20)
    - Evans-Montgomery (Box 21)
    - Montgomery-Zimmerman (Box 22)
    - Adams-Wittemar (Box 23)
  - Class of 1951
    - Abbott-Gant (Box 23)
    - Gardner-Schafer (Box 24)
    - Scherer-Zwillinger (Box 25)
  - Class of 1952
    - Abate-Denney (Box 25)
    - Dennis-Quirk (Box 26)
    - Rae-Zych (Box 27)
  - Class of 1953
    - Abbott-Dyer (Box 27)
    - Eagleston-Schwerin (Box 28)
    - Sciarra-Zukor (Box 29)
  - Class of 1954
    - Abbe-Furth (Box 29)
    - Gage-Spieker (Box 30)
    - Stamas-Zuckerman (Box 31)
  - Class of 1955
    - Abbott-Furman (Box 31)
    - Gachot-Rusnak (Box 32)
    - Sabin-Zuckerbraun (Box 33)
- Student record cards of the freshman year for the classes of 1924-1939, 1920-1939; Accession 2001-A-139
  - 1924, Aaron-Zimmerman (Box 1)
  - 1925
    - Aaron-Smith (Box 2)
    - Sniffen-Zindle (Box 3)
  - 1926
    - Adams-Myers (Box 3)
    - Naylor-Zantzinger (Box 4)
  - 1927
    - Abkowitz-Loveland (Box 4)
    - Lowndes-Zubriskie (Box 5)
  - 1928
    - Abbott-Ingham (Box 5)
    - Ives-Zozzora (Box 6)
  - 1929
    - Adam-Donnel (Box 6)
    - Dorais-Thelen (Box 7)
    - Thomas-Zimmerman (Box 8)
  - 1930
    - Abbot-Littleton (Box 8)
    - Lobb-Yinkey (Box 9)
  - 1931
    - Abell-Chapin (Box 9)
    - Chasnoff-Roath (Box 10)
    - Robbins-Zug (Box 11)
  - 1932
    - Abbot-Gerli (Box 11)
    - Gerstell-Wolcott (Box 12)
    - Waldman-Zsiga (Box 13)
  - 1933
    - Abbot-Lynch (Box 14)
    - McCutcheon-Zuckert (Box 14)
  - 1934
    - Aaron-Day (Box 14)
    - Day, Henry-Stowe (Box 15)
    - Sturges-Zimmerman (Box 16)
  - 1935
    - Abell-Hosford (Box 16)
    - Hotchkiss-Zvonkovic (Box 17)
  - 1936
    - Adams-Barker (Box 17)
    - Barnum-Zier (Box 18)
  - 1937
    - Aaron-Scott (Box 19)
    - Schutz-Zimmerman (Box 20)
  - 1938
    - Abbe-Seronde (Box 20)
    - Seybolt-Zwiebel (Box 21)
  - 1939
    - Acker-Moffitt (Box 21)
    - Mohr-Zogbaum (Box 22)